<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
 "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_SushiBasics">
<title>Sushi Basics</title>
<shortdesc>In Japanese cuisine, sushi is vinegared rice, usually topped
with other ingredients, including fish (cooked or uncooked) and vegetables.</shortdesc>
<prolog>
  <author type="contributor">joe.zucker</author>
  <critdates>
   <!--joe.zucker-->
   <revised modified="2020-12-02"/>
  </critdates>
<metadata><keywords><indexterm>sushi<indexterm>basics</indexterm></indexterm>
</keywords></metadata>
</prolog>
<conbody>
<p>The main idea in the preparation of sushi is the preservation and fermentation of fish with salt
      and rice, a process that has been traced back to Southeast Asia where fish and rice
      fermentation dishes still exist today. The science behind the fermentation of fish in rice is
      that the vinegar produced from the fermenting rice breaks the fish down into amino acids. This
      results in one of the five basic tastes, called umami in Japanese. The oldest form of sushi in
      Japan, Narezushi still very closely resembles this process. In Japan, Narezushi evolved into
      Oshizushi and ultimately Edomae nigirizushi, which is what the world today knows as sushi.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_e1d_d5b_wnb">
        <title>Sushi Ready to Eat</title>
        <image href="../img/sushi-spread.jpg" id="image_hmv_wrb_wnb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
<p>The common ingredient across all the different kinds of sushi is
sushi rice (known as shari in Japanese). The variety in sushi arises
from the different fillings and toppings, condiments, and the way
these ingredients are put together. The same ingredients may be assembled
in a traditional or a contemporary way, creating a very different
final result:<ul>
<li>Nigiri-zushi</li>
<li>Maki-zushi (roll)</li>
<li>Oshizushi </li>
<li>Chirashizushi </li>
<li>Narezushi (old style fermented sushi) </li>
<li>Temarizushi</li>
</ul></p>
</conbody>
</concept>

